lose your mind I was thinking the
difference between
summertime be possible
what you think the differences
well I think it relates to what we've
been talking about him previous tours in
recent talks so summertime seems to be
more about unifying and composing the
mind recognizing their mind can you
compose your mind without understanding
what the mind is no can you compose the
mind without seeing the mind and just by
following an external set of
descriptions of hospitals you mind
you know is that even conceivable no so
can you then compose your mind spontaneously
spontaneously
no can you compose your mind unknowingly
unnerving like that so what do all these
things have in common then the possible
so can you compose the mind without
understanding of the mind so there's no
summit that without the possible in the
reason why I ask that is because you
know I don't know how many times I
myself heard it from different people
like a general contemporary view of oh
you do your beep a sauna yeah
I'm not referring to the meditation
thinking good possibility study here do
your study and now it's time for formal
meditation wherever you go and you
follow like fortune Australis and
somehow what you studied will
miraculously fit into this experience of
non thinking and observing sensations
oh there's absolutely the two completely
different things all day or you see that
if you see no relationship between some
of them impersonal
they're not two yokes of the same thing
as the Buddha described they're
completely two different yokes
they're not even yolks could end up
pulling anything well there are yokes of
the wrong view I suppose wrong idea of
somewhat and wrong in every personal
re-enforce your wrong views of both
practices so yeah you are yoking
yourself just get away my experiment it was you
just get away my experiment it was you
do your summit er hmm because you need
to calm your mind yeah then once it's
carving off you know direct your mind to
the nature and and funnily enough all of
that is completely refuted by the Buddha
in in some of its hood and the quantity
suit is imagine Acharya says there's
absolutely no such thing as we write
meditation without a review it is
inconceivable yet here you are starting
your practice thinking what you do as a
meditation is the meditation that
pertains to the meditation of
enlightenment or whatever the rule is
teaching knowingly at the same time you
know that you have no right view but
you're thinking marble Titian is right
so what is that what would be the sole
criteria then for those people for
people who engage in such a
contradictory review yet adhere to a
certain method or technique of the
meditation knowing at the same time that
they don't have the right view they
don't know what the mind is they don't
understand the nature the mind yeah
they're practicing calming of the mind
what is the criteria for their coming oh
no I said feel pleasure yeah and that's
really when it said again and again
without a review you'll be just
meditating with your own sensuality you
cannot possibly not meditate without it
and that's not a meditation that he
approves of so think of Samhita as can
be personal and think of the personal as
active some of them literally in cetera
here but it seems to me that that I
still see too
like sort of different directions or dip
or like slight different perspective or
orientations involved in the summer to
be possible because they know so so
summertime would be so I guess like so
all all I can all that can manifest
manifest is an image had any notion of
something outside of that is also
another image clarifying that mind comes
first that direction seems to be about
well somewhat er it's whereas I would
say the passenger seems to be more I
guess their gang as they Otto social
links but the past is more about the
fact that whatever image whatever has
manifested sorry I was sorry you just
said that clarifying that thought is
what summit is I find that thought
that's what a person is clarifying that
mine comes first understanding the
nature of in a reasonably enduring image
yeah did any other relationship any
other movement any other thought in
regard to it must be within the
fundamentally manifested enduring image
that's what we passed finish just
discerning it and see they are so linked
together the you thought you were
describing one well you know the other
women so the the pastor I keep thinking
of the person as being more about the
fact that I didn't I can't own this
image this whatever it whatever whatever
has manifested sort of I was subjected
to its rather than I critical you know I
can't own this hmm that's amazing so at
the noon so summit so Savage is more
about including the totality of your
experience like not not it not um not
including my weight include like so as
an image as including what you just
clarify yeah exactly
it's not the opposite did I know it's
not the opposite direction and can't
have one without the other different
emphases of the same yeah that's for
them yeah but there is a different
emphasis that no of course that's why
they're too yo nobody says their one
thing but literally if one ball pulls
harder the other one is full bias they cannot
the other one is full bias they cannot
be separated there is no yolk without -
but what general attitude is it's
basically two separate bowls with two
separate yolks and like somehow they
magically connect okay let's do it
the only way to discern the two is
within one that's what I said two balls
are tied with one yoke so if you are
approaching you try to discern yoke by
chasing two different bowls you're not
yes first you need to understand what yoga
first you need to understand what yoga
is and then you'll see the two aspects
of it and then you'll know where the two
balls are and then you'll be practicing
some of the you know you personally
personally maintain some of them yeah
okay and some of the most accurately
would be what you just said this sermon
is like a discerner image has to endure
first doesn't matter the secondary
action choices intentions and so on the
camp will be within and you stop
assuming outside of it yeah that's your
now clarified this and context they're
also in use in the same sense the things
that have a reason on their own were
enduring that allowed you to discern the
nature of enduring now you determine
India maintaining the endurance of your
discernment is what some it is that's
what your discernment will come to
fulfillment then throw in jhanas you
fully fulfill your understanding of
things once you come there with the
right view because that's exactly what's
enduring the cleft but could you say
that could you say that the the
recognizing the unknown ability of
what's manifest me
is more awesome aspect of Vipassana
another directing capacitor but a sort
of trying to get that to that
recognition that that insight to apply
to the totality of the experience is
more the direction of some attack no you
are not applying it okay if you're
applying it means you're doing it you're
not discerning in an economy there isn't
so the reason why it feels like it's
separate directions because you keep
interjecting yourself yeah yeah yes
doing something so yeah when you have
the discernment of a person when you
talk about yeah we did that
discern the summit ah don't do it
elsewhere that's my point
see it's not accurate even on that
entirely internal personal slight shift
of your attention yeah let alone how
inaccurate it is when you do it is a
separate thing my study in my meditation
it's earth and sky yeah so when I have
like will be usually doing it well how
are you feeling right now what is the
present enduring feeling all right so
what are the characteristics of the
present enduring feeling the
characteristics just use not in mood
describing the characteristics of it in
the nature not in the content right now
fills me planned
blend what it is kind of sytems of
blindness Allah Allah
so see now you're basically discerning
and looking and lifting up and looking
around of one thing that induce yes but
now imagine I ask you what is your
current presently enduring feeling so
I'm asking you that again now okay so
what is it neutral mutual feeling okay
so um and now what is it hasn't
presently enduring feeling neutral your
truth okay so we keep talking about and I keep
okay so we keep talking about and I keep
asking you if you don't so you're not
actively thinking about the present
enduring but you're not ignoring
it's their enduring yes that's the
sometimes we go it if you're not
actively engaging with what's enduring
are you still aware of its enduring
that's why mindfulness mmm develop
correctly resulting proper force that's
what Somali develop correctly result in
fulfilling more four foundations of
mindfulness and no one would know one
would think that you could do to partner
with our mindfulness nobody would think
would you mean no one would it I don't
think anyone would argue that's we
connect too much of mine yes I do it in
the same way because the basis for what
you want to discern or it's a basis for
maintaining the enduring image of what
you discerned either way mindfulness has
to be there and you can't do too much of
it while you can as the Buddha said you
can do too much of a pasa
hey you can do too much of Samadhi as I
mean you don't make enough effort to
think about the characteristics which
remain to to a degree unclear yeah oh
you can be thinking bit too much to the
video you're becoming a bit nervous and
restless and calm as in you you come
because you're so engage with
characteristics of whatever is present
enduring you forget in the present
during thing is enduring that on its own
and it doesn't require your neck sort of
upholding it so you get a bit Restless
but either way with the right view it
will even itself out if you have to even
itself out so steady that's what is good
even if you're easily out yoke together
yes you're holding something in that
ease yeah sure to see what's going on
but then you'd have to its keen to call
me it comes down thankfully yeah
so yes I was suitably so summit is more
of that kind of passive not not
not ignoring the passive non ignoring
not engaging in with a allowing me the
right order of things yeah that you just
discerned which he couldn't do without
the apostle exactly and you wouldn't be
discerning it if it wasn't there in your
exact if you haven't recognized the
degree of things endurance and
unsanitary is not so much do they eat
living yes exact small the fact that
these things and job that's why they the
perfect summer today the burger
described is the Jonah's yeah the one
that he was praised and that's what
there is no sense of I am in them yeah
even where somebody we still not another
hunt that sense has to subside
completely before you get to develop I
because you can't be doing it and it's
about you not doing it that's why it's
so pleasant and in sublime and so on
because it doesn't require effort and
that's why it develops the servant
that's what we drive view you get jhanas
you will be at least an agony as in you
get John it means you develop your mind
to the extent to John you would be free
from sensuality and probably free from
conceit in no time
because it's just becoming fully
familiar with it as in is solid as a
rock steady the clarity of things that
did you descend you just becomes your
mode of being and then if fully becomes
apparent clear beyond doubt that there
is no room for any the slightest degree
of me and I am and me choosing to do
this
yeah whatever right there these things
are enjoying so that's that's that's the
sole reason that he felt like two
different directions for you even they
were unified with the general context as
I said it wasn't as accurate enough
because you still had a trace of idea of
now I apply it that's life you know you
don't apply it or slightly you applying
it it's a separate thing now now you can
take me applying something as there is
an image they deduce for you which give
the context of your application but
you'll be passing and Samadhi
are on the level of there is an image
not on the level of your application of
it yet hence no you can't have too much
of it the right mindfulness and it's a
necessary basis for any form of
application all discernment
yes ma'am I imagine most people think
some whatever the process is coming good
step backwards but people think that
their techniques yeah so these two
things I do do that's where you have
none if you don't have a right view
first again somebody to so tell many
other cities as well
you can't possibly practice rightly
without knowing what the right practice
is it's just a contradiction in terms
but it's such a hard thing for people to
accept as well oh yeah cuz he feels like
off so whatever I've been doing means
doesn't count for anything well you
don't know what it you will only know
whether he can't for something or not
once you get the right view in hindsight
you can see whether your practice is
counted or not are you being too afraid
to admit that it might not count for
anything is basically what's gonna
hinder you from finding what does count
for something it's just simply that fear
that you might be well even even if you
wasted all of your time twenty years of
your supposed practice it's never too
late and if the practice was right you
have nothing to fear so why feeling
questioning it you can't use from
practicing more you can only lose from
refraining to practice further because
of fear of what but when you thought you
invested in before I was just telling to
people those people it's less painful
it's less pain so again boils down to
the criteria they would have said but
Regina would only know which is
displeases me and this thing displeased
with me and that's why I follow it
that's why I rejected like even even
intellect and reasoning are heavily
rooted in pleasing displeasing that's
why I'm for it that's why I'm against
you that's why that's why fine arguments
for it that's what fine arguments
against it just because it pleases me
and they remain ignorant of that yeah
that's what I hope that beings so even
if you're following the right teaching
you're falling for the wrong reasons
yeah sure happy to be a petition